Sarita Kumari

Phone: +91 9167240252; E-mail:saritakumari2005@gmail.com

Career Objective

Work with full conviction and motivation to achieve long-term objective of constantly learning new skills and perspectives to make most efficient contribution to my work place. I believe, I grow only when my organization grows.

Experience Summary:

Total Year of Experience: 12 years 2 Months

Relevant Exp: 12 Years 2 Months Current Location: Mumbai Preferred Location: Mumbai

Current Company: HDFC Bank Ltd Year of Experience: 11 Months

Payroll Company: : HDFC Bank Ltd

Notice Period -3 month

Name of the	Years of	Duration	Role	Technical Skill Set
Organization	Experience			
HDFC Bank Ltd	11 Months	Nov 2018 - Till Date	Managing Flexcube Corporate Application Team for the release and change management. Stakeholder Management and Coordination with various internal teams.	PI/SQL,SQL,Unix,Weblogic,API ,R Software,Python,Unix,Linux,BIP Reports Development,Ansible ,FCUBS,java script
Oracle Financial	7 Years 11	Dec 2010-Nov	Flexcube	Oracle Forms, RAD Tolls , Unix , Sql
Software Services Ltd	Months	2018	Corporate Product Implementation support and Consulting in Various Banks.	PL/Sql,Java Scripting,
Wipro Technologies	3 Years 3 Months	Aug 2007- Dec 2010	Application Production Support and Maintenance	Java,Oracle,RDBMS,sql/plsql,Oracle Forms,DBA,Cobol,IBM MQ

Certification / Course

Course 1

Course Name: Advance Management Program (AMP) - From IIM Lucknow and BSE Mumbai

Duration: 1 year

Type of Course: Executive Management Course

Course 2

Course Name: Open Shift ,docker container

Duration: I week

Course 3

Course Name: Automation using Ansible

Duration: 2 weeks

Certification 1

Course Name: Machine Learning (Coursera Standford University)

Duration: 3 Months

Programming Language: Octave

Certification 2

Course Name: Business Analytics and Data Mining Using R

Institution: NPTEL (IIT Roorkee)

Duration: 3 Months

Programming Language: R Software

Project 1 :Flexcube FCUBS New Core Banking Application Support

Duration : Nov 2018 till date

Technology : Oracle 12c, Unix Reports, WebLogic, SQL/PLSQL, R Software, Python

Role : Senior Manager

Description (in brief): New Core Banking Flexcube FCUBS Product Implementation

Responsibilities (in brief): Implementation of enhancement of new Core Banking Solution Flexcube FCUBS and mentoring the team to achieve the agreed timeline for the Go live. Stakeholder Management ,Requirement Gathering ,Functional Specification and change and release management implementation .Project Management

Project 2 : Africa Region, Flexcube Product Customization and Implementation

Client : Africa Region Clients Duration : Dec 2017 to Nov 2019

Technology : Oracle 10g, Oracle Developer Suite 10g, Unix

Reports, weblogic, RAD tool, JS

Role : Team Lead

Description (in brief): Africa Region Bank Clients Flexcube FCUBS Product Customization

Responsibilities (in brief):

Responsibilities included implementation of the FLEXCUBE functionality for Africa Region Clients and guiding the team member for the FCUBS Flexcube customization .

Project 3 :Audi Bank, Lebanon Flexcube Implementation

Client : Audi Bank, Lebanon
Duration : Sep 2015 to Dec 2017

Technology : Oracle 10g, Oracle Developer Suite 10g, Unix,BIP

Reports, weblogic, RAD tool, JS

Role : Implementation Consultant

Description (in brief): FCUBS 12.1 Product Implementation

Responsibilities (in brief):

Responsibilities included implementation of the FLEXCUBE functionality for Audi Bank and guiding the team member for the same.

Project 4 FCC Customization HDFC Bank

Client : HDFC Bank, India, Honkong and Bahrain Country.

Duration : April 2013 to Sep2015

Technology : Oracle 10g, Oracle Developer Suite 10g, Oracle Forms, Unix, BIP Reports

Role : Project Manager

Description (in brief): Customization of FCC for HDFC Bank.

Responsibilities (in brief):

Responsibilities included Enhancement and implementation of the FLEXCUBE functionality for HDFC Bank and guiding the team member for the same.

Project 5: Business As Usual(BAU) Flexcube Product Application Enhancement

Client CITI BANK (Eastern Europe and Middle East Region-EMEA)

Role: Senior Consultant

Technology: SQL, PL/SQL, Oracle Forms, Unix

Roles and Responsibilities: Developing and enhancing the functionality for the FT,FX ,MM,LD and PC modules

Project Description: Enhancement/Development related to FX,MM(Money Market),PC(Payment and Collections,FT(Fund Transfer) and LD (Loan and Deposits Modules of Flexcube product for EMEA region.

Project 6: Fixed Income Charges Commodity (FICC) Implementation and Support

Client: CITI BANK (Asia Pacific Region)

Role: Implementation Support

Roles and Responsibilities:Implementation of FICC module for Indonesia and Philippines country

Technology: SQL, PL/SQL, Oracle Forms, Unix, C

Project Description: Implementation and Enhancement of FICC Product for Indonesia ,Philippines

FICC Product Enhancement for Australia and Newzeland

Previous Company: Wipro Technologies Year of Experience: 3years 3months

Project 7:

Roles and Responsibilities: Module (SQL, PLSQL)

Technology: SQL, PL/SQL, JAVA

Client: Estro Enso Project Description: Functional Requirement:

The requirement for this project was the comparison of the data between the latest production run and and latest previous run should be compared if the discrepancies between the previous run and latest run is greater than zero then the solved and comments check box in the front-end report screen should already be checked. Contribution: Solution provided for generating the discrepancies report by getting the data from the database table the comparing the discrepancies in the latest and previous production run data using the stored procedure (PL/SQL).

Front end screen was developed using JAVA technology for showing the reports based on the results on returned by PL/SQL stored procedure

Project 8:

Roles and Responsibilities: Production Application support and Maintenance

Client: Schneider Electric (US and Canada)

Technology: Oracle, Oracle Forms, SQL PL/SQL, COBOL, UNIX

Nature of work and contribution:

Interacting with client and giving solution for production issues on day to day basis

Analyzing application related issues to find the cause and solution

Application Overview:

Application1:Service Management System(SMS) is a cost accounting application system for below business process

Order Management, Purchase Order creation, Purchase Order Receiving,

Vouchering Process

Invoicing Process,

Inventory Management

Materials Management

Application2 CPD(Customer Product Data) and IDW - Industry Data Warehouse

CPD application deals in improving the processes associated with the creation and management of product data at the part number level. Also, customers enter a catalog number on-line and are able to retrieve attribute information associated with that catalog number. Use of ROY (data repository) infrastructure, provides a business platform and improved process for customer product data. Enable customers to make buying decisions based on provided content without requiring them to go to datasheets. **Application3: Autotime:-** Auto Time provides employees with time and attendance, payroll and human resources. With Auto Time, the supervisors can manage the attendance of their personnel, determine labor or material bottlenecks on the shop floor, and minimize the administration of paperwork in these areas.

Activity: DBA activities

Creating an employee dump for the Autotime vendor

Installing and configuring the Oracle client and ODBC settings

Creating an employee dump for the Autotime vendor

Creating a database dump for the Autotime vendor

Project 9 Work done using JAVA technology:

- 1. Developed system "Automated Payment System" using javascript,html,java beans and database connectivity. (JDBC)Functionality: based on banking system for an user(Debit / Credit)
- 2. Developed an application "Central Repoisitory System" based on MVC Pattern using Struts FrameWork.Application is about taking the data from the user and storing the entered user input to excel sheet and then dipaying the report using page initation in the jsp page.
- 3. Developed an application "DBDAshBoard" using struts framework and JFreeChart utility for checking the database status through various types of charts(line chart,bar chart,pie chart,meter chart) using sql query through jdbc connectivity for connecting to database FunctionalityPurpose of this Baseboard project is to monitor the performance of the Oracle Database and for taking corrective action

Education

Degree/Specialization	Institute/University	CGPA/%			
M.Tech [Industrial Engg.]	Indian Institute of Technology, Delhi	8. 875/10			
B.Tech [Production Engg and Management]	National Institute of Technology, Jamshedpur	71.28%			
XIIth	Kendriya Vidyalaya, Jamlpur	68.7 %			
Xth	Kendriya Vidyalaya ,Jamalpur	79%			

Computer Proficiency

Programming Languages:

- Oracle Forms ,python,R software,Machine Learning,Python , Octave ,Weblogic
- PL SQL,SQL, Oracle DBA activities

Scripting Language

UNIX,PERL

Key Academic Projects

• M.Tech Project : Development of Production Management Games

Production Management Games are the **decision support system** which helps managers and professionals to learn the behaviour of the System by simulating the real system scenario by varying various system parameters.

Developed four games production management games. Product Mix Game (with and without budget constraint), Single Server Production Management Game and Demand Forecasting Game.

Methodology used for developing Games are discrete event simulation and programming languageJAVA.

Ref. Prof. Arun Kanda, IIT Delhi

B.Tech Project: ABC Analysis As A Tool Of Inventory Control

Ref Prof Shashi Bhushan, NIT Jamshedpur, TISCO

- Term Projects Accomplished at IIT Delhi:
- Study of Nokia's Performance measures
- Analyze the performance of Indian Cricket Team and Individual Player

Summer Training

- Title: Value Engg. Technique As Applied To Temporary Battery Mounting Arrangement On TATA LP 1613TC.
- Organisation: TATA MOTORS, Jamshedpur

Achievements & Extra-Curricular Interests

- Secured First Rank for consecutive three semesters in M.Tech program at IIT Delhi.
- Regular participation in elocution competitions.

Personality Traits

- Honesty, hard work, determination and efficiency are some ethics that I value the most
- Listening to music are leisure time activities.